<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>prisonerjohn</title>
    <description>Works by Elie Zananiri and collaborators.</description>
    <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://prisonerjohn.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 14:27:41 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 14:27:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Zero Days VR</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The true story of a clandestine mission hatched by the US and Israel to sabotage an underground Iranian nuclear facility told from the perspective of Stuxnet, a sophisticated cyber weapon, and a key NSA informant. Audiences experience the high stakes of cyber warfare placed inside the invisible world of computer viruses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-12 col-lg-offset-0 centered nopadding&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;carousel-example-generic&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;!-- Indicators --&gt;
        &lt;ol class=&quot;carousel-indicators&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
        &lt;/ol&gt;

        &lt;!-- Wrapper for slides --&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item active&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-02.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-03.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-04.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-05.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-06.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/zero-days-vr-06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!--/Carousel --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the Participant Media feature-length documentary Zero Days Directed by Alex Gibney, Zero Days VR introduces a new dimension to the original feature by telling the story from a perspective that wasn’t possible before the emergence of virtual reality. The Zero Days VR experience visualizes the story of Stuxnet in a new way: audiences will be placed inside the invisible world of computer viruses experiencing the high stakes of cyber warfare at a human scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero Days VR tells the Stuxnet story through two main characters: the Stuxnet virus, and an anonymous NSA informant who testifies about a cyber mission hatched by allies with clashing agendas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero Days VR explores the next chapter of modern warfare through the story of Stuxnet: the first cyber weapon in the world known to cause real-world physical damage. Audiences experience the invisible world of cyber warfare through the perspective of the Stuxnet virus on a clandestine mission hatched by the US and Israel to sabotage an underground Iranian nuclear facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero Days VR highlights how this digital threat is closer to home than we realize, representing a new chapter in modern warfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;press&quot;&gt;Press&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I’m floating in cyberspace, and it’s beautiful. A tunnel of sleek metallic tubes telescopes before me, criss-crossing into TRON-like circuit board cities that make it clear that I’m inside of a computer. I’m surrounded by information: infographics pulsing red and blue below me, elongated frames of news footage zooming past my eyes, their soundbites echoing in my ears—were I not wearing a virtual reality headset I’d be sure I could reach out and touch data itself.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://creators.vice.com/en_us/article/pgq7v8/zero-days-vr-sundance-debut&quot;&gt;How to See Stuxnet? ‘Zero Days’ Filmmakers Find an Unlikely Answer in VR&lt;/a&gt; - Creators Project, Jan 26 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I had that rare feeling when I go through a VR experience and think, “This changes things.””&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vrscout.com/news/zero-days-vr-revolutionary-immersive-documentary/&quot;&gt;Become the Virus in Zero Days VR: A Revolutionary Immersive Documentary&lt;/a&gt; – VRScout, Feb 2 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Now, the team behind some of the film’s visual effects has developed a 20-minute VR adaptation of the two-hour film, and it’s just as enthralling.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcmag.com/news/354248/stuxnet-documentary-zero-days-gets-thrilling-vr-version&quot;&gt;Stuxnet Documentary ‘Zero Days’ Gets Thrilling VR Version&lt;/a&gt; – PC Magazine, Jun 12 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/zero-days-vr</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/zero-days-vr</guid>
        
        <category>experimental</category>
        
        <category>documentary</category>
        
        <category>virtual reality</category>
        
        <category>Unity</category>
        
        <category>Oculus Rift</category>
        
        <category>Sundance</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: First commit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been over 5 years since I updated my last blog so I figured it’s time for a fresh new site. Welcome to &lt;a href=&quot;http://prisonerjohn.com&quot;&gt;prisonerjohn.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is built with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, using a modified &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/st4ple/solid-jekyll&quot;&gt;Solid&lt;/a&gt; theme and hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. It has been pretty easy to use so far, so hopefully this means I’ll be updating it often.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 09:18:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//blog/first-commit</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//blog/first-commit</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Collimation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Collimation is an installation composed of two microscopes watching and recording each other and a three screen projection which visualizes the process of interpretive analysis occurring within the software. The system acts as a rudimentary form of AI, where the visual stimuli is translated - in a performative act of seeing - in the centre image (which is comprised of the two microscope feeds concatenated into one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/collimation-02.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/collimation-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting data is then transposed first to the image on the left, taking the form of a neuron and is responsive in both emergent growth and behaviour. The data chain continues, flowing to the right hand image of a neuron. In a “mirror neuron” scenario, this image is influenced by the actions of the first and independently reacts and generates its own growth patterns and behaviours.
The audio created by the apparatus itself, coupled with a composed score is introduced into the system where it too acts upon the behaviour and responsivity of the images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The systems behaviour is, in a mimetic sense, reflective of several kinds of processes which operate under acts of translation and analysis. The parsing of information, existing as it does at the very foundations of embodied cognition, is central to our understanding of the bodies, networks and ecosystems in which we exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/collimation-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/collimation-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the installation, the visual instantiation of complex notions of being collide with features of surveillance and even further into cartographic renderings of both the microscopic, in the form of neuronal imagery to the macro in terms of alluding to the mapping and visualization of connectivity (through data analytics) within socio-geo-politcal bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;press&quot;&gt;Press&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The data is first transposed in the centre image, combining the two microscope feeds, then extracted to the image on the left and “flowing” to the right as a “mirror neuron” where the image is influenced by the actions of the first, reacting and generating its own growth patterns and behaviour.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativeapplications.net/openframeworks/collimation-two-interlocked-microscopes-stimulate-artificial-neural-growth/&quot;&gt;Collimation – Two interlocked microscopes stimulate artificial neural growth&lt;/a&gt; – CreativeApplications.net, Oct 20 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/collimation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/collimation</guid>
        
        <category>experimental</category>
        
        <category>installation</category>
        
        <category>projection</category>
        
        <category>camera</category>
        
        <category>openFrameworks</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Fraction Mash</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An iPad app allowing you to explore fractions by creating hilarious and dazzling photo mashups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mashing up images is engaging and fun. With Fraction Mash, you directly manipulate the fractions that control the way the pictures are partitioned. Attend closely to the fractions themselves and develop a deep intuitive understanding of fractions. App features include using photos from the library or camera, multiple grid options (squares, rows, columns, pie slices, triangles, etc.), overlays, photo blending, and sharing of images to social networks and NYSCI gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fraction Mash is part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://noticing.nysci.org/&quot;&gt;Noticing Tools&lt;/a&gt;, a suite of iPad apps that make learning math and science irresistible through play, creative design projects, and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-12 col-lg-offset-0 centered nopadding&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;carousel-example-generic&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;!-- Indicators --&gt;
        &lt;ol class=&quot;carousel-indicators&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
        &lt;/ol&gt;

        &lt;!-- Wrapper for slides --&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item active&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/fraction-mash-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/fraction-mash-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/fraction-mash-02.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/fraction-mash-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/fraction-mash-03.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/fraction-mash-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/fraction-mash-04.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/fraction-mash-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!--/Carousel --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/fraction-mash</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/fraction-mash</guid>
        
        <category>cultural</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
        <category>camera</category>
        
        <category>iOS</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Learning Lab: Mars Base</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Learning Lab exhibit at &lt;a href=&quot;http://museum.governmentsummit.org/&quot;&gt;Museum of Future Government Services&lt;/a&gt; envisions an immersive educational environment offering dynamic course topics on demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stepping out of the bright street through a dark threshold you are surrounded by an alien landscape. Sharp winds and radio transmissions crackle in the background as you stare through the panoramic eyes of a robotic rover. Signs of life scatter the harsh Martian landscape before you. Picking up the interaction device you are greeted by an assistant named DATA who offers to help guide you through a curriculum exploring aspects of the recently established settlement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did the Astronauts get here? What is a day on Mars Base like? As you follow your curiosity deeper into the questions, real time data continually streams in, peppering the landscape throughout the 360-degree view. Your lesson completes. Upon stepping back onto the street, you are invited to attend next week’s course: The Great Barrier Reef.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/learning-lab-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/learning-lab-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A specific cliff side in the Candor Chasma region of Mars’ Valles Marineris rift valley was selected based on ideal locations for human settlement on Mars. The Martian landscape visualization was generated with elevation and color data from HiRise - a telescopic camera attached to NASA’s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter, a satellite currently in orbit around Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design team engaged &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bryanversteeg.com/&quot;&gt;Bryan Versteeg&lt;/a&gt;, a specialist in 3D renderings of future space habitats for humanity. Together we visualized a plausible colony based on current research and near future technology. Versteeg designed the essential elements of a life sustaining habitat including a greenhouse, living quarters, energy generating facilities, and transportation rovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A database of Mars facts drove the web of question and answer pairs, allowing visitors to explore a natural and personal course of inquiry. Each entry point to the system was presented in landscape in the form of small animations or objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/learning-lab-02.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/learning-lab-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2015 Museum of Future Government Services is a project by the Prime Minister’s Office of the UAE directed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tellart.com/&quot;&gt;Tellart&lt;/a&gt; with an international team of top design studios including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.specular.cc/&quot;&gt;Specular&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://softlabnyc.com/&quot;&gt;SOFTlab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bompasandparr.com/&quot;&gt;Bompas &amp;amp; Parr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.octopd.com/&quot;&gt;Octo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ideeundklang.com/&quot;&gt;Idee und Klang&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://futurecities.catapult.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Future Cities Catapult&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The onsite build and installation was done by Tellart in collaboration with Publicis Live, Neumann Miller and Projex.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/learning-lab</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/learning-lab</guid>
        
        <category>cultural</category>
        
        <category>installation</category>
        
        <category>360</category>
        
        <category>dome</category>
        
        <category>projection</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
        <category>openFrameworks</category>
        
        <category>iOS</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Middlebury Athletics History Wall</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An interactive photo wall permanently installed in the Virtue Field House at Middlebury College, providing users with an interactive experience through the annals of sports at the College. More than 6000 photos, clippings, and ephemera culled from Middlebury’s archives are included in the collection, spanning over one hundred years of history. Images are categorized by topic and decade, through which filters can be created for generating slideshows on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-05.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wall consists of an array of 12x5 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.christiedigital.com/en-us/microtiles&quot;&gt;Christie MicroTiles&lt;/a&gt; fitted with a touch kit for interactivity. The application runs in two modes: Hero mode, where high resolution images take over the entire wall, slowly cycling through a slideshow; and Grid mode, where the wall is split into 4 interactive scrolling timelines, allowing visitors to browse through the collection and read additional information about each image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-12 col-lg-offset-0 centered nopadding&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;carousel-example-generic&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;!-- Indicators --&gt;
        &lt;ol class=&quot;carousel-indicators&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
        &lt;/ol&gt;

        &lt;!-- Wrapper for slides --&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item active&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-02.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-03.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-04.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/middlebury-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!--/Carousel --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/middlebury</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/middlebury</guid>
        
        <category>cultural</category>
        
        <category>wall</category>
        
        <category>MicroTiles</category>
        
        <category>openFrameworks</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Parade</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Parade is an interactive art installation born out of the collaboration between interaction design studio Dpt. and ceramic artist Laurent Craste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coarse wooden structure confronts us in the exhibition space. In this relic, which appears to have once been a sumptuous interior, remain only two porcelain vases; limp, slumped, exhausted, as having been forgotten there a long time ago. From the top of the structure hangs a work light, dangling under our noses and dimly illuminating the desolate scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/parade-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/parade-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visitors are encouraged to swing the suspended light, which causes the shadows cast by the vases to come alive on the wall, swaying to the rhythm of the movement. With time, the vases become aware of each other, and a relationship forms between them. The tone of the swings will determine if a combat or dance scene unfolds in front of the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like shadow theatre, Parade presents the fantastic spectacle of the vase silhouettes which, in a tragicomic ballet, try to regain their original form, their past glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/parade-02.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/parade-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;press&quot;&gt;Press&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Parade is an interactive art installation conceived by ceramist Laurent Craste and digital agency Dpt. for the Chromatic festival in Montreal. At first glance the piece looks rather mundane: two misshapen porcelain vases sit atop a pedestal inside a wood cube, lit from above by an industrial light. But move the light and suddenly the magic happens as shadows projected from the vases animate to life. What a fun piece.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisiscolossal.com/2014/05/dancing-shadow-sculptures-by-dpt-and-laurent-craste/&quot;&gt;Dancing Shadow Sculptures&lt;/a&gt; – This is Colossal, May 30 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You know how to turn crooked vases into an interesting art installation that remind us of Beauty and the Beast’s singing pots and candlesticks? We’d like to say magic, but since we don’t live in a Disney movie, the right answer is motion tracking and real-time 3D rendering.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2014/06/05/art-projector-dancing-shadows/&quot;&gt;Computer trickery makes these shadows dance&lt;/a&gt; – Engadget, Jun 5 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/parade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/parade</guid>
        
        <category>experimental</category>
        
        <category>installation</category>
        
        <category>shadows</category>
        
        <category>openFrameworks</category>
        
        <category>Unity</category>
        
        <category>Kinect</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Stream Me Up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stream Me Up is an installation allowing the experience we have always desired: the ability to transport ourselves to new worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying new developments in three dimensional scanning and virtual reality, visitors are given the opportunity to create a gestural message intended for the inhabitants of far-away planets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon stepping into the center of an illuminated space station, travelers see their own image rendered before them on a spaceship platform. Detecting their presence, the teleporters lights flash, prompting the visitor to act a six second 3D transmission — a Vine for aliens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-anim.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the transmission capture is complete, the avatar is beamed away from the space station platform. The viewer is led to an Oculus Rift editing station. There they witness their transmission and, using gaze based interaction, teleport themselves to several other planets; encountering a few native inhabitants along the way. The edited transmission results in an animated GIF of their journey to share on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-02.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stream Me Up utilizes four calibrated DepthKit rigs streaming in real time. Visitors are captured in three dimensions from four perspectives, resulting in a full body reconstruction that appears holographic. This true volumetric scan is perfect for representation of the human form in virtual reality, and allows the viewer to see themselves appear in alien landscapes within the Oculus Rift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-12 col-lg-offset-0 centered nopadding&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;carousel-example-generic&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;!-- Indicators --&gt;
        &lt;ol class=&quot;carousel-indicators&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
        &lt;/ol&gt;

        &lt;!-- Wrapper for slides --&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item active&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-03.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-04.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-05.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/stream-me-up-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!--/Carousel --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/stream-me-up</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/stream-me-up</guid>
        
        <category>commercial</category>
        
        <category>installation</category>
        
        <category>360</category>
        
        <category>virtual reality</category>
        
        <category>openFrameworks</category>
        
        <category>Kinect</category>
        
        <category>Oculus Rift</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: CLOUDS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;CLOUDS is an interactive documentary and a portrait of this community of digital pioneers, explored through the lens of code. The project asks questions about the future of creativity at a time when algorithms play an important role in shaping culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People featured in the film include 40 artists, designers and hackers who participate in the co-creation of free tools for creative expression: &lt;a href=&quot;https://processing.org/&quot;&gt;Processing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://openframeworks.cc/&quot;&gt;openFrameworks&lt;/a&gt;. Reflecting the story of these online communities, the software behind CLOUDS was built in C++ using openFrameworks, and includes real-time interactive visualizations by the artists featured in the documentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its revolutionary hybrid format, somewhere between a documentary, a videogame, and data visualization, CLOUDS allows viewers to navigate a web of ideas. It uses a data-driven Story Engine to present an endless ever-changing conversation, where artists co-exist with their code, presented through real-time interactive visual systems and lush 3D environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project has been presented at prestigious film festivals and museum exhibitions as both an installation and a cinematic experience for a live audience. It’s now available as a software application for audiences at home to download and explore on their personal computers, OS X or PC, with the option of viewing in Oculus VR. The techniques explored in CLOUDS suggest a possible future of storytelling that brings interactive graphics, visual effects and cinema closer together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/clouds</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/clouds</guid>
        
        <category>experimental</category>
        
        <category>installation</category>
        
        <category>virtual reality</category>
        
        <category>openFrameworks</category>
        
        <category>Kinect</category>
        
        <category>Oculus Rift</category>
        
        <category>Sundance</category>
        
        <category>Tribeca</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project: Échos</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Échos is a participatory and interactive installation that challenges our perceptions and enhances the richness of the French language through places and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A giant lenticular screen shines brightly in the centre of the space, surrounded by four booths. The central structure has four distinct viewing angles, on which curated films by 12 directors from around the world are broadcast, interspersed with video responses left by visitors to the exhibit. The booths allow guests to watch the films individually and to record their own video messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation is accompanied by a website – &lt;a href=&quot;http://echos.onf.ca/&quot;&gt;echos.onf.ca&lt;/a&gt; – that takes the form of a colourful mosaic in which all 22 short films from the installation are available, sorted by emotion, country or location, as well as all of the visitors’ video testimonials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-12 col-lg-offset-0 centered nopadding&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;carousel-example-generic&quot; class=&quot;carousel slide&quot; data-ride=&quot;carousel&quot;&gt;
        &lt;!-- Indicators --&gt;
        &lt;ol class=&quot;carousel-indicators&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;active&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
                &lt;li data-target=&quot;#carousel-example-generic&quot; data-slide-to=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
                &lt;/li&gt;
            
        &lt;/ol&gt;

        &lt;!-- Wrapper for slides --&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;carousel-inner&quot;&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item active&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-02.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-03.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-04.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
                &lt;div class=&quot;item&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a data-rel=&quot;prettyPhoto&quot; href=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-05.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/echos-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!--/Carousel --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://prisonerjohn.com//project/echos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prisonerjohn.com//project/echos</guid>
        
        <category>cultural</category>
        
        <category>installation</category>
        
        <category>projection</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
        <category>mapping</category>
        
        <category>openFrameworks</category>
        
        <category>iOS</category>
        
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
